秋葉原のラジ館前です
人工衛星の墜落から
５日が経過した
今日も 朝から 大勢の人が
見物に詰めかけていますが
放置されたままの人工衛星は
依然として 国籍等不明のまま
It's been five days since the satellite fell onto
the Akihabara Radio Building.
撤去のめどは立っておりません
Since morning, many people have gathered here
again today to see it.
But the satellite's origins remain unknown,
and there's no timetable
for when it will be taken down.
Mail Received
ちょっと よろしいですか？
今日は
人工衛星の見物でしょうか？
どちらから いらっしゃったのか
よろしければ…
あっ… ああ…
はぁっ はぁっ…
Could I have a moment?
はぁっ はぁっ はぁっ…
Are you here to see the satellite?
Would you tell us where you've come from?
あっ！
あ… はぁ…
Butterfly Effect's Divergence
おお～！
これが…
This is it?
おいしい！
It's delicious!
阿万音氏 牛丼 初めて？
Miss Amane, you've never had gyuudon?
うん ウワサには聞いてたけど
おいしいね！
No. I'd heard rumors of it.
It's delicious.
フンッ 生卵をかけると
もっと うまくなるぞ
It's even better if you put a raw egg on it.
貴様も 戦士なら
一人で牛丼屋くらい
If you call yourself a warrior,
you should be able to come to
a gyuudon place by yourself.
入れるようにしておいた方がいい
なっ…！
ああ～！
あ～あ…
Well, Daru and I come here often.
まっ 俺もダルも
この店には よく来る
誘われれば
いつでも つきあうがな
If you invite us, we'll go with you anytime.
ああ！ 思い出したお！
I remember!
この前 オカリンの牛皿
僕が立て替えたんだった
Last time, I had to pay for Okarin's meal.
そんなこともあったかもしれんな
It's possible that happened, yes.
｢あったかも｣じゃなくて
あったよ！ 返してよ お金！
It's not just possible! It happened!
Give me back my money!
あいにく 今日は持ち合わせがない
Sadly, I've none on me today.
俺だ 至急 スイス銀行の口座に
金を振り込んでくれ
It's me.
Transfer the funds to my Swiss bank account.
なんだと!? 機関が
ジュネーブのサーバーに…
What?
The Organization hacked into
the Geneva servers?
携帯禁止
No cell phones.
How terrible...
あの カッコだけですよ…
Um, he's just pretending.
トゥットゥル－！
うん？
鈴さんも一緒だったんだ
So you were with them, too, Suzu-san?
ちょうど お昼の休憩だったから
It was time for my lunch break.
もう少し早ければ
一緒に食べられたのにね
If you'd been a bit earlier, you could've joined us.
じゃあ
明日の昼は みんなで行く？
Then, you want to all go together tomorrow?
今度は オカリンのおごりで…
なんだと！
I'm sure Okarin would be happy to pay
What?
機関の妨害工作で
サーバーの復旧に１週間かかる！
The Organization's sabotaging the process,
and it will take one week
to bring the servers back online?
あっ 紅莉栖ちゃんだ
あっ！
It's Kurisu-chan!
おお 助手
昨日は ゆっくり休めたか？
Assistant, did you get some sleep?
｢助手｣って言うな
Don't call me assistant.
うん？
おい バイト
昼飯 済んだら とっとと働け！
Hey, part-timer.
If you're done with lunch, get back to work.
何なの？
What's with her?
円卓会議？
うむ
A round table?
Indeed.
何ぞ？ それ
What's that?
A meeting of lab members.
ラボメンによる ミーティングだ
そんなん やったことあったっけ？
We ever do one before?
そもそも
円卓なんか どこにあるのよ
Do you even own a round table?
実物はない
Not a physical one.
だが 我ら ラボメンの
心の中にはある そうだろう？
But the round table lies
within all lab members' hearts.
Right?
｢そうだろう？｣じゃなかろうが
Whether it's true or not,
勝手に ひとの心の中に
変なもの持たせないで
don't put anything weird in my heart.
まゆしぃの心の中にもあるかな？
Do you think there's one in Mayushii's heart, too?
ああ あるさ
Yes, there is.
そっか～ よかった
でも 円卓って なぁに？
Is there?
Yay!
But what's a round table?
ていうか なんで 円卓？
アーサー王？
Why a round table?
Are you supposed to be King Arthur?
そもそも 私は
ラボメンといっても 期間限定だし
I'm only a temporary lab member anyway.
とにかく！ 円卓会議だ
まゆりにも
At any rate...
It's time for a round table.
We need to tell Mayuri about the
situation we find ourselves in.
俺たちの置かれた状況を
伝えておく必要がある
状況って？
Situation?
というわけで
ＳＥＲＮを出し抜くために 我々は
And so,
in order to beat SERN, we must perfect
一刻も早く 電話レンジ(仮)の
タイムマシン機能を
the Phone Microwave (name subject to change)
完璧なものにしなくてはならない
as soon as possible.
へえ… まゆしぃには難しすぎて
よく分からないのです
It's too hard for Mayushii to understand!
とにかく
ＳＥＲＮは悪だということだ
Just know that SERN is evil.
But how do we perfect it?
う～ん… だけど
｢電話レンジ(仮)を完璧に｣って
僕ら メールを過去に送る実験には
成功してね？
We've succeeded in sending
messages to the past, right?
たったの２回だけだ
Only twice!
しかも どのようなときに
その現象が発生するか
And we don't know under what conditions
まだ 分かっていない
the phenomenon occurs.
う～ん… この前の実験だと
From what we observed last time,
放電現象が起きたときだけ
送れたお
it only occurs when there's electricity.
うん…
Right!
あっ そうだ！
うん？ 何か分かったの？
Did you find out something?
No. "Mails Sent to the Past" is too long.
いや ｢過去へ送れるメール｣では
言いにくい
まずは 名前を付けるところから
始めようではないか
First, we need to find a name for them.
はあ？ また カッコつけ？
｢また｣とか言うな！
Another failed attempt to sound leet?
Don't say "another"!
この鳳凰院 凶真をバカにして…
Do you dare mock the great Hououin...
どうせ へんてこな名前を
付けたいだけでしょ
You'll just give it a stupid name anyway.
失敬な！ ならば 発表しよう
How rude!
Then I'll tell you.
俺は この ｢過去へ送れるメール｣
という現象について
I've given this name to the phenomenon
of e-mails going back in time...
こう 名付けた その名も…
I call it "Nostalgia Drive"!
｢ノスタルジアドライブ｣！
ちなみに
｢時を越えた郷愁への旅路｣と書き
You write it with the kanji for
"journey crossing over time,"
｢ノスタルジアドライブ｣と
読ませる
but you read it "Nostalgia Drive."
分かりにく 却下
Too complicated.
Rejected.
貴様！ 助手の分際で
却下できる権限があると思って…
Hey, you're the assistant, you can't reject
なら 多数決にする？
Then let's have a vote.
｢時を越えた郷愁への旅路｣に
賛成の人
Who agrees with "Nostalgia Drive"?
えっ？
裏切ったな！ まゆり ダル！
Et tu, Mayuri? Daru?
紅莉栖ちゃんの
言うとおりだと思うよ
I think Kurisu-chan is right.
まゆしぃは
そんな長い名前 覚えられません
Mayushii can't remember a long name like that.
厨二病すぎだろ 常考
なっ…
It's like something invented by an
emo teenager fixated on sci-fi.
分かりやすさを重視すべきね
We should focus on making it easy to understand.
時をさかのぼるメールだから…
Since it's an e-mail going back in time,
｢遡行メール｣でいいんじゃない？
｢遡行｣って なぁに？
we could call it "Mail That Flies Against Time."
What's "flies against time"?
ちっとも
分かりやすくないではないか
That's not easy to understand at all.
ここは ｢時をかけるメール｣の
一択だろ 常考
It should be "The Mail That Leapt Through Time."
少し表現が固いな 言いにくい
It's a bit formal.
And hard to say.
あんたが言うな！
You don't get to say that.
Your "Nostalgia whatsit" was long, too!
オカリンのﾉｽﾀﾙｼﾞｱ何とかだって
長いじゃんか！
ロマンがあればいいのだ
ロマンが！
It's romantic! If it's romantic, it's okay!
じゃ 略して ｢時かけ｣で
So we can shorten it to TimeLeap.
Then we don't know what leapt through time!
それでは
何が時を駆けるのか分からん
メールなのか 少女なのか
それとも バナナなのか？
Is it an e-mail? A girl? A banana?
トゥットゥルー！
まゆしぃも思いついたよ
Mayushii has an idea!
あのね ｢バックトゥザメール｣！
Um... "Back to the Mail"!
直訳すると ｢メールに戻る｣
意味不明だ
That would be going back to the e-mail,
not back in time.
That doesn't make sense.
じゃあ ｢デロリアンメール｣！
ますます分からんわ！
Then "DeLorean Mail"!
That makes even less sense!
ねえ
うん？
Hey...
Why don't we just shorten it to "D-mail"?
もう いっそのこと 略して
｢Ｄメール｣でいいんじゃない？
なっ…
おお それ いいね
I like that.
じゃ 決定ということで
Okay, it's decided then.
We will now begin the experiments
with D-mail (name subject to change).
それでは これより
Ｄメール(仮)の実験を開始する
(仮)も略す方向で
We can also cut the "(name subject to change)."
作戦名は
｢過去を司る女神作戦｣と…
The operation is called Operation Urd.
We don't need that, either.
それも要らない
But we don't know what it takes
to make the D-mail happen.
だけど Ｄメールの発生条件
分かってないじゃん
放電現象との関係も不明だし
Or what it's got to do with electricity.
フフフ… それを
これから 確認しようというのだ
That's what we're going to find out.
この 鳳凰院 凶真に
一つ 仮説がある
I, Hououin Kyouma, have an idea.
俺たちは 最も単純にして
We forgot the simplest and
most important condition.
最も決定的な条件を
見落としていた すなわち…
In other words, the time it occurred!
発生時刻だ！
The first D-mail was between 12:00 and 13:00.
最初のＤメールは 12時から13時
２回目は 18時ごろに発生している
The second occurred around 18:00.
つまり その２つの時間帯に
実験することで
If we attempt to replicate it at those times,
we will succeed.
再現が可能！ かもしれない
Possibly.
いくら何でも単純すぎだろ 常考
That's gotta be too simple.
試してみる価値はある
まゆり バナナを！
It's worth trying.
Mayuri, the banana!
まゆしぃのバナナ 随分 減ったね
Mayushii's running low on bananas.
バナナまで入れる必要あるの？
Do we have to put the banana in?
バナナまで入れる…
"Put the banana in!"
ダル 今は控えろ
Daru, not now.
ゼリーマンになるかどうかの
確認のためだ
I want to see if it turns into a jellyman.
さあ 助手 早く！ バナナを中へ
Now, assistant.
Put the banana inside.
バナナを中へ…
いいかげんにしろ このHENTAI！
"Put the banana inside"...
Enough, you pervert!
ごめんね 後で 新しいバナナ
買ってくるから
I'm sorry.
I'll buy you a new banana later.
ホント？ うれしいな
Really?
I'm so happy!
オカリンや ダル君はね
Okarin and Daru never buy me any.
ちっとも
買ってきてくれないのです
Jeez, you two...
ホントに もうっ… あたたた…
Ow!
ドジっ子アピールは よせ
しとらんわ！
Stop trying to show what a klutz you are.
I'm not!
うう…
痛いの痛いの飛んでけ～
Pain, pain, go away!
サンクス まゆり
Thanks, Mayuri.
そこ いつまでも
百合フィールドを作っていないで
Stop making a Yuri Field and prepare the D-mail.
Ｄメールの準備を
はいはい
Right.
Is 120 seconds okay for the time?
時間設定は 120秒で おｋ？
うむ
｢過去を司る女神作戦｣ 開始！
Indeed.
Begin Operation Urd!
今だ！
Now!
うっ…
フハハハハ…！
きた… きたぞ～！
It's here.
It's here!
バナナは？
うん？
Where's the banana?
ゲルバナになったね
It's a gel-bana!
おお～！
フフ… ハハハハ…！
ついに解明したぞ
やはり 俺の予想どおり
I've solved it at last.
As I thought,
Ｄメールの発生条件は
時間だったのだ！
time was the D-mail's missing factor!
やるわね 岡部
あまりに単純で気付かなかった
Nice job, Okabe.
It was so simple, I didn't notice.
んんっ… 悔しいのか？
Does it bother you?
それでも 俺に賛辞を送る
その姿勢は 評価してやろう
Still, I respect you for having the guts
to gaze upon me so admiringly.
フハッ フハッ…
それより Ｄメールは届いてる？
Anyway, did the D-mail arrive?
うむ 成功だ
It did.
受信日時は５日前
It says it was sent five days ago.
牧瀬氏 ２通 送った？
Did you send two messages, Miss Makise?
ううん １通だけ
No, just one.
２通に分割されてる…
It's split into two messages.
ちなみに この文章の意味は？
えっ？
By the way, what does this message mean?
自分で調べれば？
Look it up yourself.
そういえばさぁ
Come to think of it,
この間のＤメールも分割されて
文章は途中で切れてたよな
the last D-mail was also split
into multiple messages,
and some of it was lost.
さかのぼった時間も
同じく ５日だったし…
And it went back in time five days, too.
ああ 何か法則性が… あっ
Yeah, there's some kind of rule to it.
Which means that D-mail...
ということは あのメールは…
頭 空っぽのバカだということか！
...was calling me an empty-headed idiot?
気付くの遅すぎ
Took you a while.
Curse you, Christina. Taking advantage of a...
おのれ クリスティーナ
どさくさに紛れて… あっ
ちょっと待て
こんなに買って どうする？
Wait a minute. Why are you buying so much?
食料は
保存の利くカップ麺で十分だろう
The only food we need is
non-perishable cup ramen.
One bag of the cheap chocolate is plenty.
チョコも 徳用のが１袋あればいい
だって 実験成功のお祝いだし…
I'm celebrating our experiment's success.
いいから 戻してこい
Go put it back.
Cheap-ass.
ちぇっ ケチくさ～
ああ…
あっ…
That's right.
そうだ 実験成功と浮かれていたが
I was so happy about the
experiment's success, I forgot.
俺たちは
ＳＥＲＮの恐ろしい機密を
We learned SERN's terrifying secret.
知ってしまったのだ
And I even involved Mayuri.
まゆりまで巻き込んでしまって
本当に よかったのか？
Was this really for the best?
あっ…
うん？
It's Shining Finger.
閃光の指圧師ではないか
What?
何だ？
さっきから 何をしている？
What are you doing?
携帯 持ってないの？
You don't have your cell phone?
The great Hououin Kyouma's cell phone is
この 鳳凰院 凶真の携帯は今
人類史に名を残す偉大な実験に
使用中のため
currently being used for an experiment that
will be remembered throughout history.
It's not here.
ここにはない
お待ち遠～ と？
O-O-Okarin!
オッ オッ… オカリン
うん？
Who's that sweet-ass...
そちらの エロい… あっ いや
I mean sexy... 3D girl?
セクシーな３次元の女性は
どなたでありますか？
I'll introduce you.
ふむ 紹介しよう
閃光の指圧師 桐生萌郁だ
This is Shining Finger, Kiryuu Moeka.
よ よろしく 桐生氏…
H-Hi, Kiryuu
３次元に希望を持っていた時期が
僕にもありますた
Even I once had hope for the 3D world.
おっ ちい～っす！
うん？
Yo!
Are you guys doing something fun?
ひょっとして
さっきから 愉快なことしてる？
Indeed.
いかにも 俺たちは 人類史に
名を残すであろう実験を…
We are performing an experiment
that will become legendary
名を残すのはいいけどさ…
うん？
Legendary is fine...
But the boss is really pissed off.
店長が
すっごく イライラしてるわけ
２階からの震動が すごくってさ
He says the vibrations from
the second story are really bad.
｢家賃１万円アップするぞ こら！｣
とか何とか
"I'll raise your rent 10,000 yen!"
he was saying.
なっ… １万円…
10,000 yen?
Okay, leave this to me.
よし ここは俺に任せろ
ダルは 助手に
Tell my assistant to stop the
experiments for a moment, Daru.
しばらく実験をやめるよう
伝えてくれ
Roger.
了解 あんた 今 最高に輝いてるよ
You're shining like never before...
牧瀬 紅莉栖も まだ いるの？
Is Makise Kurisu still there?
うん？ ああ そういえば
さっきも じっと見てたな
Oh, yeah. You were staring
at her back there, weren't you?
この前といい
なぜ ヤツに こだわる？
So, what happened earlier?
What's your deal with her?
Did something happen in the past?
過去に 何かあったのか？
Nothing in the past, no.
過去には 何もない…
そう あれは８歳の夏
Yes, it was the summer we were eight.
ミシシッピの河川敷で
逃げ出したアカミミガメ…
And on the dry riverbed of the Mississippi,
your red-eared slider ran away...
It was nothing!
何もないって！ この前が初見！
I saw her for the first time earlier!
それより 早く
店長に謝りに行った方がいいよ
Anyway, you should go see the boss.
ぬう…
What are you doing upstairs?
お前ら
いったい 上で 何 やってんだ？
さっきから
何度も 派手に揺らしやがって
It's been shaking like an earthquake.
We're performing an experiment
that will rewrite scientific history.
実は 人類の科学史を塗り替える
世紀の実験中でしてね
But don't worry.
しかし ご安心を
今日は もう これ以上は… あっ
We won't do any more today...
やめろと言ったのに… ううっ！
I said stop!
何をしてるか！
実験は中止だと言ったろう！
What are you doing?
I said stop!
最後に もう一回だけって
牧瀬氏が…
Miss Makise said to let her
do it just once more.
メールしたんだけど 見てない？
I sent you a message. Did you see it?
Of course not!
見られるわけなかろうが！
I warned you five days ago...
５日も前に忠告したのに
ふざけるな！
Don't be stupid
Oh, when we weren't doing the experiments,
あっ あと なんか 実験以外でも
オカリンの携帯 何度も鳴ってたよ
your phone went off a bunch of times.
うん？
Shining Finger
Really!
Sorry!
Shining Finger
Are you maybe...
How've you been?
Shining Finger
?
Well?
Shining Finger
Hey
How've you been?
Okabe-kun
Shining Finger
Well?
Find out
anything about
the IBN 5100?
くうっ… なんで 直接 言わんか！
Why didn't she just ask me?!
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
何だか分からないけど
I don't know,
but he's probably not getting enough calcium.
カルシウム 足りてないみたいね
誰のせいだ！
Whose fault is that?
Well, I got plenty of data,
まっ データは 十分 取れたし
and I pretty much figured out the rules
for how the D-mail works.
Ｄメールの法則についても
大体 分かったから いいけど
なにっ！
What?
Send a modified command to the
microwave's heading function (reverse spin)
Each second on the timer
represents one hour back in time.
Ｄメールが
さかのぼる時間については
Open the microwave door while heating
(Timing -> Unconfirmed)
Electricity
タイマーの１秒が
現実の１時間に相当する
While the electricity is sparking,
send message to the phone
Prerequisites to making the electricity appear?
(time between 12:00 PM and 18:00 PM?)
Number of characters that can be sent
with a D-mail -> (12 half-width, 6 full-width) x3
You can control the time the Phone Microwave
(name subject to change) sends a message back.
120 seconds is 5 days.
120秒で５日
それで ５日前ってわけ
One second on the timer = One hour in reality
At the same time, anything placed into the
Phone Microwave becomes a jellyman
(teleportation confirmed, as well)
It's amazing that she figured out how to
control how far it goes back, isn't it?
いつ送るか 調整できるの
発見したのは すごくね？
But the maximum amount of information that can
be sent back is 36 English characters
だが 送れる文字数は
英文で 最大36文字
or 18 Japanese characters.
日本文で18文字だ
It's too small.
少なすぎる 改善したいところだな
I'd like to fix that.
I'm sure you can't send anything too big,
きっと 大きなものとか
たくさんは送れないんだね
or send too much.
あっ もしかして その
Maybe that Curb black hole...
カーブ･ブラックホールが…
カー･ブラックホールね
The Kerr black hole, right.
そのブラックホールの穴が
きっついんだよ
The hole is too tight!
まゆ氏 今の言葉 もう一度
｢穴｣のところから…
Can you repeat that, Mayushii?
The part about the hole?
やめろ HENTAI！
Shut up, pervert!
Anyhow, we can work on the details
tomorrow and going forward.
とにかく
詳細な検証は明日以降に行う
But I'll say this:
だが これだけは宣言しておこう！
August 2, 2010,
2010年８月２日は
is a day that mankind will remember forever!
人類史にとって 永遠に
記憶に残る日になるであろう
なぜなら この日
我ら 未来ガジェット研究所は
For the Future Gadget Lab
has succeeded in developing humanity's
人類史上初のタイムマシン開発に
first time machine!
成功したからであ～る！
初じゃなくね？
ＳＥＲＮに 先 越されてたし
It's not the first one, right?
SERN beat us.
そもそも 開発したとはいえない
We didn't "develop" it, anyway.
It was all coincidence.
偶然 使えるようになっただけ
ぐぐ… どいつも こいつも…
All of you, disrespecting my great declaration...
俺の堂々たる宣言に
敬意すら払わんとは…
But Okarin...
でも オカリン
うん？
I'm glad your experiments worked.
実験が うまくいって よかったね
あ…
Where am I?
ここは…
あ… あっ！
う… うわっ！
あっ ああっ…
You're not moving.
あんたは移動なんてしていない
ああっ…
Time and space have changed places here.
ここでは
空間と時間が入れ換わっている
The event horizon?
事象の地平線か…？
You can't move through space.
あんたは
空間を移動することはできない
時間だけが
延々と引き延ばされている
And time is extended forever.
One second of your time
will be an eternity for me.
あんたの１秒が 私には永遠となる
The end of space is running away?
宇宙の果てが逃げている…
いや 違う 引き延ばされている
No, it's not. It's being extended.
What is?
何が？ 宇宙が？ 俺が!?
The universe?
Or me?
振り返ってはいけない
永遠は無限ではない
You mustn't look back.
Eternity isn't infinite.
Even if time extends toward eternity,
永遠に向かって
時間が引き延ばされようとも
終わりは存在する
an end still exists.
ああっ…
When will it be one second later?
１秒後は いつ やってくる？
Look forward.
前を向いて たどり着いて
Reach the end.
You mustn't turn back.
振り返ってはいけない
あ… ああ…
うう…
That mail freak again?
また メール魔か
相変わらずのしつこさ
Her persistence...
Shining Finger
You there?
It's dark
Shining Finger
Wake up
I'm here
Shining Finger
You asleep?
It bug you?
Shining Finger
Sorry for yesterday
Moeka
Sorry for yesterday.
Can I come see you?
｢これから そっちへ行っていい？｣
Shining Finger
I'm here
At least answer me.
Or are you pretending
not to be there?
Moeka
It didn't occur to you that I was asleep?
まだ寝てるとは考えないのか？
Shining Finger
Wake up
Were you asleep?
Moeka
I was!
もしかしなくても寝てた… うん？
Shining Finger
It's dark
I'm coming up the
stairs right now.
Moeka
What?
なんだと!?
あっ？
Shining Finger
I'm outside.
I'll knock.
If you're there,
respond.
Moeka
あっ…
あ…
Shining Finger
You said I could
come see, right?
Moeka
Why use your cell phone?
なぜ メールする？
目の前にいるのに
I'm right here.
見ないぞ 直接 言え
I'm not looking at it. Just say it.
I can show you,
but I didn't think you'd come this early.
見せるのはいいが
こんな朝っぱらから来るとは…
I get it!
あっ そうか 貴様 本当の狙いは
この俺の取材だな！
You're really after an interview
with me, aren't you?
なぜ しゃべらない？
Why don't you talk?
なるほど そういうことか
I see... So that's it.
You're terrified of Mad Scientist
Hououin Kyouma's sinister aura!
この俺
狂気のマッドサイエンティスト
鳳凰院 凶真の 邪悪なるオーラを
恐れているのだな！
フッハハハハ…！
It's easier to send mails...
メールの方が気楽 だから…
So show me the IBN 5100.
IBN5100 見せてほしいの…
Very well.
いいだろう！
しかし 見せるだけだ
But I'm just showing it to you.
Once you've seen it, leave!
そして 見たら帰るのだ
それでいいか？
Is that all right?
あ…
Is she just a retro-PC fan?
こいつ もしかして
ただの レトロＰＣマニアか？
あっ？
Shining Finger
Let me take a picture
Moeka
んっ うん…
But not my face.
俺の顔以外だ
If you photograph my face,
もし 撮ったら
お前の口封じをするしかな…
I'll have to silence you forever...
うん？
Shining Finger
Please!
I'd like you
to loan it
to me, okay?
I'd be happy
if you'd help
me carry it.
Moeka
I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?
I'd be happy if you'd help me carry...
なぜ
貸すのが前提になっとるのだ！
Why am I suddenly lending it to you?
And if you really want me to loan it to you,
then look at me and say it.
それに 本当に貸してほしいのなら
こっちを向いて 直接 話せ
貸して… くれるの？
You'll loan it to me?
Sadly, no.
残念ながら ダメだ
I'm only borrowing it myself.
そもそも 俺も
一時的に借りただけだ
When I'm done,
使い終わったら
元の所有者に返すことになる
I have to return it to its original owner.
元の所有者って？
Its original owner?
Yanabayashi Shrine.
柳林神社だ
Guten Morgen.
グーテンモルゲ～ン！
うわ 確か 昨日の桐生氏？
You're Miss Kiryuu from yesterday, right?
I didn't introduce you yesterday, did I?
昨日は 紹介していなかったな
My favorite right arm, Super Haker Daru.
頼れる右腕
スーパーハカーのダルだ
It's "Hacker," man. Seriously.
だから ｢スーパーハッカー｣だって
Anyway, I thought I'd improve
the Phone Microwave a little.
あっ そうそう それより
電話レンジ ちょっと
改良しようと思うんだよね
It's currently a bit of a pain in the ass, right?
今 結構
めんどい手順が必要じゃん？
Sending the D-mails to the past.
Ｄメールを過去に送るのにさ
うっ！ あっ…
Shining Finger
What does he mean,
"sending mails
to the past"?
Moeka
I-It's nothing.
なっ… 何でもない 聞き違いだ
You misheard.
He didn't say, "sending mails to the past."
｢過去にメールを送る｣
ではなくてだな
He said, "Sen Dingma Ils Tot Hepast,"
｢カ･コニ･メエル･オクール｣
と言ったのだ
これは 今は失われし
古代シュメール語で
which is ancient Sumerian for
"Did you eat breakfast?"
｢朝ごはん もう食べた？｣の…
トゥットゥルー！
Good morning, Okarin!
おはよう オカリン
タイムマシン実験する前に
Can Mayushii use the microwave before you
to make her kara-age?
まゆしぃの から揚げ
温めさせてほしいな
Okabe, I had an idea about the time machine.
岡部 タイムマシンのことで
一つ 思いついたんだが…
It's me.
俺だ マズいことになった
This is bad.
No.
いや そうじゃない
８号機の情報が第三者に漏れた
Information about #8
has been leaked to a third party.
どういう状況？
What's going on?
He's totally ignoring all three of us?
僕たち全員 華麗にスルー？
We can't let the Organization find out...
機関に知られるわけにはいか…
通話中にメールを送るな！
Don't mail while I'm on the phone!
Was that maybe...
ひょっとして…
えっ？
うん？
Shining Finger
It can't be
It can't be FB?
FB?
｢ＦＢ｣？ あっ？
分かった
こうなったら 全てを話そう
Very well. I'll tell you everything.
秘密を知られたからには
しかたがない
Kiryuu Moeka,
桐生萌郁 貴様は 今日から
from now on, you're Lab Member 005!
ラボメンNo.005だ！
ええっ！
おお…
フッ